we can make sense of the powers of three
by starting with one triangle taking
three copies to form this triangle with
three small triangles taking three
copies of that to represent three
squared and so on each time taking three
copies of the previous diagram to
produce the next power of three if we do
that here's a representation for three
to the N plus one but now let's see
something interesting we can take two
copies of three to the n and stack them
next to each other on top of that take
two copies of three to the N minus one
like this and keep going until we have
two copies of three squared on top of
that we place two copies of three and
finally we place two copies of one if we
then stack one last copy of one on top
it turns out that we produce the exact
same diagram as the diagram for three to
the N plus one so we get equality
between these two formulas from this
equality we see that the sum where I
ranges from zero to n of three to the I
must be three to the N plus one minus
one over two this is a formula for the
geometric sum of the powers of three